Howard W. and Jean Lipman
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Howard and Jean Lipman Art Collection, 1954-2000, undated, Series 2:; (Boxes 3-15, 12 linear feet)
  - Painters of Interest, 1955-1978, undated, 2.4:
    - Hultberg, John, 1955-1964, undated (Box 14)
    - Johnson Ray, 1963-1970, undated (Box 14)
    - Katzman, Herbert, 1955-1961, undated (Box 14)
    - Kinigstein, Jonah, 1959-1962 (Box 14)
    - Martin, Keith, 1956-1960 (Box 14)
    - Motherwell, Robert, circa 1961-1969 (Box 14)
    - Mueller, George, 1955, 1961, undated (Box 14)
    - Pozzatti, Rudy, 1955-1962 (Box 14)
    - Sheeler, Charles, 1969, undated (Box 14)
    - Stella, Frank, 1968-1970 (Box 14)
    - (Box 14)
  - Folk Art Collection, 1848, 1938-1981, undated, 2.5:
    Documents within this subseries include notebooks and journals that detail folk art purchases, photographs and slides of works, correspondence with individuals, museums, and organizations, invoices for purchases of art work, inventory lists, and miscellaneous printed material. Arrangement of the subseries is alphabetical by subject heading. Documents within folders are arranged chronologically by year, with the exception of the notebooks. The notebooks are erratic in their chronological order and include overlapping years
    - Catalog of Works (Box 14)
      - Drawings, 1938-1951 (Box 14)
      - Miscellaneous Items, 1938-1951 (Box 14)
      - Oil Paintings, 1938-1951, (2 folders) (Box 14)
      - Pastels, 1938-1951 (Box 14)
      - Sculpture (Metal Objects), 1938-1951 (Box 14)
      - Sculpture (Wood Carvings), 1938-1951 (Box 14)
    - Catalog of Works (Box 15)
      - Tokens and Memorial Jewelry, 1938-1951 (Box 15)
      - Watercolors, 1938-1951, (2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Correspondence, 1945-1960 (Box 15)
    - Fenimore House, New York State Historical Association, 1950-1951 (Box 15)
    - Insurance Receipts, 1948-1950 (Box 15)
    - Inventory Lists, undated (Box 15)
    - Loans of Artwork, 1948-1950 (Box 15)
    - Miscellaneous Material, 1848, 1946-1948, undated (Box 15)
    - Photographs (Box 15)
      - Collection in Situ, Wilton, Conn. Residence, undated (Box 15)
      - Sculpture, 1938-1965, undated, (2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Purchases and Sales of Works, 1938-1962 (Box 15)
    - Sale and Disposition of Collection, 1946-1981, undated (Box 15)
- Artists Files, 1916-1998, undated, Series 3:; (Boxes 15-18, 46-47, OV 50-52; 3.6 linear ft.)
  The documents in this series reflect the Lipman's ongoing interest in the careers of Alexander Calder, Louise Nevelson, and David Smith. Correspondence includes letters to and from the artists, as well as letters to and from other individuals or institutions, regarding projects involving the artists. Also represented in this series are exhibit brochures and announcements, interviews, writings by and about the various artists, and associated printed material.
  The documents within each subseries are grouped by record type, and thereafter, chronologically by year.
  The series is comprised of three subseries, as follows:
  3.1: Alexander Calder, 1924-1998, undated
  3.2: Louise Nevelson, 1916-1980, undated
  3.3: David Smith, 1954-1974, undated
  - Alexander Calder, 1924-1998, undated, 3.1:
    Documents within this subseries consist of correspondence to and from Calder; occasional drawings, posters, and prints; photographs of the artist and his works; newspaper and magazine articles about the artist and his works; editorial material regarding books about Calder that Jean Lipman edited; and miscellaneous publicity material regarding the artist. Included within these files are some original, unpublished works by Calder for various projects that Jean Lipman initiated.
    Overall arrangement is alphabetical by subject heading. Material within folders is arranged chronologically by year. Oversized materials are listed at the end of the subseries.
    - Alexander Calder and His Magical Mobiles, 1981-1994, undated (Box 15)
    - Animal Sketching, 1973 (Box 15)
    - Auction Catalogs, Christies, Oct. 1991-Mar. 1998, undated, (2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Auction Catalogs, Sotheby's, 1986-1997 (Box 15)
    - Calder and Socrate, 1976-1980 (Box 15)
    - Calder Calendar (See also Box 46), 1981, 1995, (2 folders) (Box 15)
    - Calder Commemorative Stamp, 1983-1998 (Box 15)
    - Calder Creatures Great and Small, 1983-1985 (Box 15)
    - "Calder in Paris: The Circus and Surrealism," Archives of American Art Journal, 1988 (Box 15)
    - Calder's Calders, 1985 (Box 15)
    - Calder's Circus (Box 16)
      - Book, 1972 (Box 16)
      - Correspondence, Miscellaneous, 1971-1975, undated (Box 16)
      - Correspondence, Permissions, 1971-1972, undated (Box 16)
      - Cover Proofs, circa 1971 (Box 16)
      - Notes, 1971-1995, undated (Box 16)
      - Permissions, 1970-1972, undated (Box 16)
      - Photographs for the Book, 1924-1970, undated (Box 16)
      - Publicity, 1972, 1992, undated (Box 16)
    - Calder's Universe (Box 16)
      - Book Editions (See also Box 46), 1980, 1989 (Box 16)
      - Correspondence, 1975-1995, undated (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous Related Material (See also Box 50), 1976-1977 (Box 16)
      - Notes, 1977 (Box 16)
      - Printed Material, 1976-1982, undated (Box 16)
      - Reviews, 1976-1989, undated (Box 16)
    - Catalogue Raisonne, 1993-1994, undated (Box 16)
    - "Celebrating Calder," Whitney Museum of American Art, 1991 (Box 16)
    - Correspondence, General (Box 16)
      - Calder, Alexander, 1958-1976, undated, (2 folders) (Box 16)
      - Guerrero, Pedro E., 1985-1998 (Box 16)
      - Miscellaneous, 1958-1998, undated, (2 folders) (Box 16)
      - Whitney Museum of Art, 1962-1998, undated (Box 16)
    - Drawings (See Box 50), 1970-1974, undated (Box 16)
    - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1977-1998, (3 folders) (Box 16)
    - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1977-1998 (Box 17)
    - Florentine Films Project, 1994-1996 (Box 17)
    - "Flying Colors," Calder Bicentennial Jet Commission, 1973-1979, undated, (2 folders) (Box 17)
    - La Grande Vitesse, Grand Rapids, Mich., 1968-1994, undated (Box 17)
    - Loans Re Calder Works of Art, 1962-1996 (Box 17)
    - Magazine Articles and Newspaper Clippings, 1977-1988, undated (Box 17)
    - Memorials and Obituaries, 1976-1977 (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous Material, 1963-1997, undated, (2 folders) (Box 17)
    - Mountains and Clouds Sculpture, 1976-1987, undated (Box 17)
    - Notes, Miscellaneous, 1968-circa 1998, undated (Box 17)
    - The Peculiar Dog, Photocopy of 1925 Calder Book, circa 1992 (Box 17)
    - Photographs and Slides (Box 17)
      - Calder's "Mailbox" in His Studio (See Box 51) (Box 17)
      - Longnose, 1974, undated (Box 17)
      - Miscellaneous (See also Box 46), circa 1944-1975, undated, (2 folders) (Box 17)
      - Wire Figures, undated (Box 17)
    - Posters and Prints (See Box 52), 1956-1975, undated (Box 17)
    - Press Releases, 1964-1973, undated (Box 17)
    - Printed Material Featuring Calder Artwork, 1961-1998, undated, (3 folders) (Box 17)
    - Traveling Calder Exhibition, 1994, undated (Box 17)
    - Miscellaneous Oversized Material, 1944-1995, undated (Box 46 (sol))
    - Calder, Miscellaneous Oversized Material, 1970-1974, undated (Box 50 (OV))
    - Calder's "Mailbox" in His Studio, undated (Box 51 (OV))
    - Calder, Posters and Prints, 1956-1975, undated (Box 52 (OV))
  - Louise Nevelson, 1916-1980, undated, 3.2:
    This subseries includes correspondence to and from Nevelson, exhibition announcements and catalogs, photographs, audio interviews, and printed material related to Nevelson's career. Arrangement is alphabetical by subject heading. Material within folders is arranged chronologically by year. Oversized materials are listed at the end of the subseries.
    - Biographical Information, 1967-1980, undated (Box 17)
    - Correspondence, 1960-1988, undated (Box 18)
    - Exhibition Announcements, Catalogs, and Press Releases, 1960-1995, undated, (2 folders) (Box 18)
    - Interviews (See also Box 47), 1959-1985 (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous Material, 1953-1988, undated (Box 18)
    - Nevelson's World (See also Box 47), 1983-1985, undated (Box 18)
    - Photographic Copies of the Artist and Her Works, 1916-1974, undated (Box 18)
    - Photographs, 1959-1975, undated (Box 18)
    - Printed Matter, 1958-1980, undated, (3 folders) (Box 18)
    - "Windows to the West," 1973 (Box 18)
    - Nevelson, Miscellaneous Oversized Material, 1973-1983 (Box 47 (Sol))
  - David Smith, 1954-1974, undated, 3.3:
    This subseries includes correspondence between Howard Lipman and Smith, general correspondence regarding Smith works and exhibitions, exhibition announcements and catalogs, photographs, reviews, and printed material related to Smith's career. Arrangement is alphabetical by subject heading. Material within folders is arranged chronologically by year.
    - Catalogs, 1958-1967, undated (Box 18)
    - Correspondence, Archives of American Art Photo Project, 1961-1966 (Box 18)
    - Correspondence, General, 1958-1971 (Box 18)
    - Correspondence, Lipman, Howard H., 1958-1964 (Box 18)
    - Exhibition Announcements and Press Releases, 1959-1972 (Box 18)
    - Magazine Articles, 1954-1973, undated (Box 18)
    - Miscellaneous Material, 1972, undated (Box 18)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1961-1973, undated (Box 18)
    - Photographs and Slides, David Smith at Voltri, Italy, 1965 (Box 18)
    - Photographs and Slides, Miscellaneous, 1955-1974, undated (Box 18)
    - Reviews, 1966-1967 (Box 18)
- Research and Writings Files, 1925-1997, undated, Series 4:; (Boxes 18-28, 48, OV 50, 53; 10.3 linear ft.)
  This subseries chronicles the research and writing activities of Jean Lipman. Documents within the series include correspondence regarding the publication of Lipman's many articles and books about Jurgan Frederick Huge, Rufus Porter, and other folk art artists and topics; general correspondence on research areas related to folk art; permissions; slides and photographs; notes and miscellaneous printed material that served as publication and resource materials for the various books; publicity and book reviews; drafts and printed versions of articles; and miscellaneous financial material related to her published books. Overall arrangement of the series is by research project. Material within subseries is arranged by subject heading. More information on arrangement can found in the description of each subseries listing.
  The subseries is divided into the following subseries:
  4.1: Jurgan Frederick Huge, 1970-1987, undated
  4.2: Rufus Porter, 1925-1981, undated
  4.3: [Samuel] Wood Gaylor, 1930-1969
  4.4: Folk Art, 1925-1997, undated
  4.5: Other Writings and Research Projects, 1932-1994, undated
  - Jurgan Frederick Huge, 1970-1987, undated, 4.1:
    Documents within this subseries include correspondence; notes and printed materials used as source material; permissions; slides, negatives, and photographs; a reading copy of the finished work; Rediscovery: Jurgan Frederick Huge, and reviews and newspaper clippings promoting the book. Arrangement is alphabetical by subject heading. Material within folders is arranged chronologically by year.
    - Correspondence, 1970-1980, undated, (3 folders) (Box 18)
    - Cover Illustration, American Heritage, 1974 (Box 18)
    - Notes and Research Materials, 1971-1975, undated (Box 18)
    - Permissions for Antiques Magazine Article, 1986-1987 (Box 19)
    - Photographs, Slides, and Transparencies, 1972, 1978, undated (Box 19)
    - Publicity Material, 1973, undated (Box 19)
    - Rediscovery: Jurgan Frederick Huge, 1973 (Box 19)
    - Text and Illustration Notes, undated (Box 19)
  - Rufus Porter, 1925-1981, undated, 4.2:
    Documents within this subseries include correspondence; notes and printed materials used as source material; permissions; slides, negatives, and photographs; reading copies of the finished works; and reviews and newspaper clippings promoting the books. Arrangement is alphabetical by subject heading. Material within folders is arranged chronologically by year.
    - Background Material, 1938-1988, undated (Box 19)
    - Correspondence (Box 19)
      - Forsyth, David P., 1961-1967 (Box 19)
      - General, 1936-1980, undated, (8 folders) (Box 19)
      - Murals, 1968-1980, undated, (5 folders) (Box 19)
      - Non-Mural Works, 1968-1980, undated (Box 19)
    - Correspondence (Box 20)
      - Publication of Rufus Porter Rediscovered (pub. 1980), 1979-1980 (Box 20)
      - Publication of Rufus Porter, Yankee Pioneer (pub. 1968), 1968-1974, undated (Box 20)
      - Search for Publisher for Rufus Porter, Yankee Painter (pub. 1950), 1944-1952 (Box 20)
    - Essential Truth (Photocopy of Porter Booklet), undated (Box 20)
    - Financial Material, 1968-1969 (Box 20)
    - Graphics and Illustration Material (See also Box 53), undated, (2 folders) (Box 20)
    - Hudson River Museum Exhibition on Porter, 1979-1980, undated (Box 20)
    - Low, Sam, Thesis on American Primitive Painting, 1964 (Box 20)
    - Material for Use in Revised Edition, undated (Box 20)
    - Miscellaneous Related Material, 1954, undated (Box 20)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities Grant Application, 1978-1979 (Box 20)
    - Negatives, 1945, 1968, undated (Box 20)
    - Newspaper and Magazine Clippings, circa 1968-1980, undated (Box 20)
    - Notes, 1940-1980, undated, (3 folders) (Box 20)
    - Patents, undated (Box 20)
    - Photocopies of Illustration Material, undated (Box 20)
    - Photographs (Box 20)
      - Alternate Views Not Used, 1967, undated (Box 20)
      - Miscellaneous Views, undated (Box 20)
      - Murals and Paintings, 1925-1968, undated, (3 folders) (Box 20)
    - Photographs (Box 21)
      - Murals and Paintings, 1925-1968, undated (Box 21)
      - Painted Objects, undated (Box 21)
      - Rufus Porter, undated (Box 21)
      - Rufus Porter Rediscovered, circa 1980, (5 folders) (Box 21)
    - Press Releases and Publicity, 1968-1980 (Box 21)
    - Radio Program Tape Recording, 1970 (Box 21)
    - The Rediscovery of Rufus Porter," The Magazine Antiques, Jan. 1981 (Box 21)
    - Research Notes of Howard Lipman, 1945 (Box 21)
    - "Rufus Porter, 1792-1884," Galley from Unidentified Publication, 1979 (Box 21)
    - Rufus Porter Rediscovered (Box 21)
      - Corrections for New Edition, 1972-circa 1980, undated (Box 21)
      - Hardcover Edition, 1980 (Box 21)
      - Paperback Edition with Corrections, 1980 (Box 21)
      - Reviews, 1980 (Box 21)
    - Rufus Porter, Yankee Pioneer (Box 21)
      - Bibliographic References, 1948-1968 (Box 21)
      - First Edition, 1968 (Box 21)
      - Mailing Lists, 1968, undated (Box 21)
      - Outline, circa 1950 (Box 21)
      - Reviews and Publicity, 1968-1969, undated (Box 21)
      - Typescripts, 1950, undated, (2 folders) (Box 21)
    - Rufus Porter, Yankee Wall Painter (Box 21)
      - Monograph, 1950 (Box 21)
      - Plate Captions, circa 1950 (Box 21)
      - Typescript, circa 1950, (2 folders) (Box 21)
    - "Rufus Porter, Yankee Wall Painter," Art in America, 1950 (Box 21)
    - Slides, 1964-1968, 1980, undated (Box 21)
    - Whitney Museum of American Art Exhibition of Porter Murals, 1968 (Box 21)
    - Porter, Graphics and Illustration Material, undated (Box 53 (OV))
  - [Samuel] Wood Gaylor, 1930-1969, 4.3:
    Documents within this subseries include correspondence; notes and printed materials used as source material for an article published in Art in America magazine; and an autobiographical typescript. Arrangement is alphabetical by subject heading. Material within folders is arranged chronologically by year.
    - Exhibitions and Miscellaneous Related Material, 1930-1969 (Box 22)
    - Typescript of Autobiography, 1953 (Box 22)
  - Folk Art, 1925-1997, undated, 4.4:
    Documents within this subseries include correspondence; notes and printed materials used as source material for a variety of books and articles authored or edited by Lipman; permissions; drafts; proofs; slides, negatives, and photographs; reading copies of the published books; stencil patterns used in American Folk Decoration; and reviews and newspaper clippings promoting Lipman's folk art related books. Arrangement is alphabetical by subject heading. Material within folders is arranged chronologically by year.
    - American Folk Art in Wood, Metal, and Stone (Box 22)
      - Correspondence, 1946-1949, undated, (4 folders) (Box 22)
      - Hardcover Edition, 1948 (Box 22)
      - Notes and Miscellaneous Material, 1947-1948, undated (Box 22)
      - Publicity and Reviews, 1948-1949 (Box 22)
    - American Folk Decoration (Box 22)
      - Correspondence, 1949-1951, undated, (5 folders) (Box 22)
      - Draft, circa 1951 (Box 22)
      - Editorial Material, Miscellaneous, undated (Box 22)
      - Hardcover Edition, 1951 (Box 22)
      - Notes and Background Material, 1948-1950, undated (Box 22)
      - Photographs, undated (Box 22)
      - Proofs, circa 1951 (Box 22)
      - Publicity and Reviews, 1951 (Box 22)
      - Stencil Patterns, undated (Box 22)
    - American Folk Decoration (Box 23)
      - Stencil Patterns (See also Box 48), undated, (2 folders) (Box 23)
    - American Folk Painting (Box 23)
      - Contract, 1965 (Box 23)
      - Correspondence, 1965-1968, undated (Box 23)
      - Draft, undated (Box 23)
      - Hardcover Edition, 1987 (Box 23)
      - Illustrations and Photographs (for Introduction), undated (Box 23)
      - Illustrations and Photographs (Primitives), 1939, undated, (2 folders) (Box 23)
      - Illustrations and Photographs (18th c.), undated (Box 23)
      - Illustrations and Photographs (19th c.), undated (Box 23)
      - Illustrations and Photographs (20th c.), undated (Box 23)
      - Miscellaneous Material, 1944-1997, undated (Box 23)
      - Notes, undated (Box 23)
      - Proofs, circa 1966 (Box 23)
      - Publicity and Reviews, 1967-1968 (Box 23)
    - American Primitive Painting (Box 23)
      - Hardcover Edition, 1942 (Box 23)
      - Miscellaneous Material, 1965, undated (Box 23)
      - Notebook, undated (Box 23)
      - Paperback Edition, 1972 (Box 23)
      - Publicity and Reviews, 1942-1946 (Box 23)
    - Five Star Folk Art, 1987-1994, undated, (2 folders) (Box 23)
    - The Flowering of American Folk Art, Book Editions, (See Box 48) 1974, 1977, 1987 (Box 23)
    - The Flowering of American Folk Art, Concurrent Exhibit at Whitney Museum of American Art, 1974-1975 (Box 23)
    - General Correspondence, A-H, 1938, 1940-1942, (3 folders) (Box 23)
    - General Correspondence, J-Z, 1943-1989, (14 folders) (Box 24)
    - J.O.J. Frost Exhibition, 1948, undated (Box 24)
    - Karolick Collection Photographs, undated (Box 24)
    - Miscellaneous Material on Folk Art, 1943-1965, undated (Box 24)
    - Native Tradition in American Art (Proposed Book) (Box 24)
      - Correspondence, 1947-1950, undated (Box 24)
      - Miscellaneous Material, 1946, undated (Box 24)
      - Photographs and Notes (Ellsworth Miniatures), 1940-1943, undated (Box 24)
      - Photographs and Notes (Furniture and Decorative Arts), 1965-1977, undated, (2 folders) (Box 24)
    - Native Tradition in American Art (Proposed Book) (Box 25)
      - Photographs and Notes (Furniture and Decorative Arts), 1965-1977, undated, (4 folders) (Box 25)
      - Photographs and Notes (Non-Primitives and Comparisons), circa 1941-1942, undated (Box 25)
    - Photographs (Box 25)
      - Anonymous Artists, Animals, undated (Box 25)
      - Anonymous Artists, Boats and Seascapes, undated (Box 25)
      - Anonymous Artists, Interior Scenes, undated (Box 25)
      - Anonymous Artists, Landscapes, undated, (2 folders) (Box 25)
      - Anonymous Artists, Miscellaneous Works, undated (Box 25)
      - Anonymous Artists, Mourning Scenes, undated (Box 25)
      - Anonymous Artists, Portraits (Children), undated (Box 25)
      - Anonymous Artists, Portraits (Couples), undated (Box 25)
      - Anonymous Artists, Portraits (Family), 1975, undated (Box 25)
      - Anonymous Artists, Portraits (Female), 1969, 1974, undated (Box 25)
      - Anonymous Artists, Portraits (Male), undated (Box 25)
      - Anonymous Artists, Still Lifes, n.d (Box 25)
      - Identified Artists, A-C, 1951-1965, undated, (2 folders) (Box 25)
      - Identified Artists, D-G, 1947, 1973, undated, (2 folders) (Box 25)
      - Identified Artists, H-O, 1948, 1979, undated, (2 folders) (Box 25)
      - Identified Artists, P-W, 1970-1979, undated, (2 folders) (Box 25)
    - Photographs (Box 26)
      - Miscellaneous Works, undated (Box 26)
      - Sculpture, 1968, undated, (4 folders) (Box 26)
    - Primitive Painters in America (Box 26)
      - Correspondence, 1949-1950 (Box 26)
      - Drafts, circa 1950 (Box 26)
      - Goldsmith, Deborah, 1942, undated (Box 26)
      - Hardcover Edition, 1950 (Box 26)
      - Jennys, J. William and Richard, 1925, undated (Box 26)
      - Miscellaneous Material, 1949-1950, undated (Box 26)
      - Pinney, Eunice, 1936-1943, undated (Box 26)
    - Printed Matter, 1932-1969, (7 folders) (Box 26)
    - Reproductions of Folk Art Works, 1942-1977, undated (Box 26)
    - Royalties, 1952-1967 (Box 26)
    - Young America: A Folk Art History, (See also Box 48) 1986-1996, undated, (2 folders) (Box 26)
    - Oversized Folk Art Material, 1986-1987, undated (Box 48 (Sol))
  - Other Writings and Research Projects, 1932-1994, undated, 4.5:
    Documents in this subseries include drafts and published versions of articles and forewords; a reprint of Lipman's master's thesis; correspondence; and notes and printed material used as source material. Arrangement is alphabetical by subject heading. Material within folders is arranged chronologically by year.
    - Art Address Book (edited by J. Lipman), 1973 (Box 26)
    - Articles by Jean Lipman (Box 27)
      - "Asahel Powers, Painter," 1958-1959 (Box 27)
      - "Benjamin Greenleaf, New England Limner," 1946-1947 (Box 27)
      - "Coca-Cola," 1964-1979, undated, (2 folders) (Box 27)
      - "Collector's Luck," 1946-1948 (Box 27)
      - "Early Days at Art in America," 1991-1993, undated (Box 27)
      - "A Folk Art Collector Confesses Some Embarrassing Errors," 1989-1990 (Box 27)
      - "Fourth of July Art," 1953-1956 (Box 27)
      - "Make Your Own Antique Chest," 1951-1952 (Box 27)
      - Miscellaneous Publications, 1932-1991 (Box 27)
      - "Money for Money's Sake," 1968-1979, undated, (3 folders) (Box 27)
      - "Period Rooms-The Sixties and Seventies," circa 1970 (Box 27)
      - "Primitive Vision and Modern Design," 1944-1945 (Box 27)
      - "Recalled Encounters," 1990-1991, undated, (2 folders) (Box 27)
      - "Remembering Edward Steichen," 1991-1994, undated (Box 27)
    - Calder's Universe: see 3.1: Alexander Calder, 1924-1998, undated (Box 27)
    - Exhibition Text, 1957-1980 (Box 27)
    - The Florentine Profile Portrait in the Quattrocento (Master's Thesis), 1936 (Box 27)
    - Forewords and Miscellaneous Book Entries, circa 1944-1991 (Box 27)
    - Ideas for Art Exhibitions, 1964-1975, undated (Box 27)
    - Ideas for Future Publications (Box 27)
      - Around the World in Eighty Ways (Book Proposal), 1978-1984 (Box 27)
    - Ideas for Future Publications (Box 28)
      - Around the World in Eighty Ways (Book Proposal), 1978-1984 (Box 28)
      - Easy Art for Pleasure and Profit, 1987-1989, undated, (2 folders) (Box 28)
      - Emperor's New Clothes, circa 1987 (Box 28)
      - Flag Article, 1990 (Box 28)
      - Golf Book, 1985 (Box 28)
      - Miscellaneous Proposals and Ideas, 1980-1994, undated (Box 28)
      - Native Tradition in American Art (See 4.4: Folk Art), 1925-1997, undated (Box 28)
    - Indian Calendar (edited by J. Lipman), 1983, (2 folders) (Box 28)
    - Provocative Parallels, 1961-1994, undated, (3 folders) (Box 28)
    - Reviews and Editorials, 1950-1991 (Box 28)
    - Samaras Album, 1970-1971, undated (Box 28)